Guide to the Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics, 1970s-1990s LATINAMER.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Latin American Countries, I.
  - Nicaragua, 9.
    - Webb, Gary. America's 'crack' plague has roots in Nicaragua war: Colombia-San Francisco Bay Area drug pipeline helped finance CIA-backed Contras Mercury Center - San Jose Mercury News, August 18, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Norton, Elizabeth. Education in Nicaragua from Tacho to Violeta, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - ICODE, Institute for Nicaraguan Studies. Encuesta nacional sobre: Los derechos humanos en Nicaragua y sobre La Procuraduria para la defensa de los derechos humanos, February 1996 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Smith, Steven Kent. Renovation and Orthodoxy: Debate and transition within the Sandinista Front for National Liberation (Draft), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Smutko, Gregorio. Los Capuchinos entre Los Miskitos, 1915-1995 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Dore, Elizabeth. Rethinking the Sandinista Legacy. In These Times, September 2, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Zamora, Augusto. (Introduction to his new book.) Relaciones con USA: Camino de Doble Via, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Sahr, Robert. U.S. Network Television News' Framing of the 1990 Nicaraguan Elections. Political Communication Research: Approaches, Studies, Assessments: Volume II. Ablex Publishing Corporation, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Hemisphere Initiatives. Democracy and Its Discontents: Nicaraguans Face the Election, October 1, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Los Retos de Aleman, January 12, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Emails on Nicaragua Elections, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Zub, Roberto. Rol de la iglesia y religion en las elecciones 96 en Nicaragua, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - U.S. State Department. Nicaragua country report on human rights practices for 1996, January 30, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - McCoy, Jennifer and Shelley McConnell. Nicaragua: Beyond the Revolution. Current History, February 1997 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Scruggs, T.M. 'Vamos a la carga:' the musical negotiation of the local and the global in Sandinista Nicaragua. prepared for LASA Conference, 1997 (do not cite), April 1997 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Ortega, Ninette Morales. Dos momentos en la produccion de viviendas y el funcionamiento de mercado de suelo urbano en Nicaragua 1979-1996, April 1997 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Stein, Andrew J. La labor pastoral y la Opcion Preferencial por los pobres en la Iglesia Catolica de Nicaragua, March 11, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Torres, Sylvia. Identity, Ethnic Resistance and Tradition in Sutiaba, Nicaragua, April 17-19, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Grupo Civico Etica y Transparencia. Valoracion final sobre el proceso electoral 1996. Volumen I, March 1997 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Grupo Civico Etica y Transparencia. Soporte estadistico: valoracion sistematica del formulario ?que observe? Volumen II, March 1997 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Spence, Jack, draft of Report on the October 20, 1996 Nicaraguan Elections. Hemisphere Initiatives, April 1, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Zimmerman, Matilde. The Political Idea of Carlos Fonseca, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Nicaragua Network. Report on Structural Adjustment (ESAF) policies in Nicaragua, August 4, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Consejo Supremo Electoral de Nicaragua, figures and charts for presidential election of 1996, November 23, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Stein, Andrew J. La labor pastoral y la Opcion Preferencial por los pobres en la Iglesia Catolica de Nicaragua, March 11, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Stein, Andrew J. The consequences of the Nicaraguan Revolution for Political Tolerance: Explaining Differences Among the Mass Public, Catholic Priests and Other Elites. Comparative Politics, May 1997 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Stein, Andrew J. Religion, Democratization and Support for the Political System in Central America: The Experience of Nicaragua, El Salvador, and Costa Rica in the 1990s, April 10, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Stein, Andrew J. A letter to the editor of the Wall Street Journal regarding Nicaragua, April 29, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Hegg, Manuel Ortega. El Regimen de Autonomia en Nicaragua: Contradicciones Historicas y Debates Recientes. Centro de Analisis Socio-Cultural, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Institute for Nicaraguan Studies. La Gobernabilidad en Nicaragua. Encuesta nacional realizada del 01 al 09 de abril de 1997: Prinicipales hallazgos, May 1997 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Institute for Nicaraguan Studies. Educacion para la paz, la democracia y los derechos humanos en Nicaragua: las agendas de la sociedad civil desde el nivel local, April 1997 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Insitute for Nicaraguan Studies. La Gobernabilidad en Nicaragua. Encuesta nacional realizada del 01 al 09 de abril de 1997: Informe final. Mayo 1997, May 1997 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Collection of articles from Confidencial. No. 52, Del 13 de al 19 de julio de 1997, July 13-19, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Abu-Lughod, Deena. Regional variations in agrarian conflict in post Sandinista Nicaragua: old tactics, new actors and national politics, Paper for 18th annual LASA congress, March 10-12, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Nicaragua E-mail/electronic info. Feb. 97 - Sept. 97, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Carter Center. Report on the pre-electoral mission to Nicaragua of the Council of Freely Elected Heads of Government, June 7-11, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Govt of Nic., Ley de Servicio Militar Patriotico La Gaceta. Diario Oficial, October 6, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Patriotic Military Service Ready Press Release, Embassy of Nicaragua, October 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Jozef Goldblat and Victor Milan, The Honduras-Nicaragua Conflict and Prospects for arms control in Central America, SIPRI Yearbook, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Nicaragua E-mail/Electronic Info, November 16, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Noticias de Nicaragua en Sintesis. April 4 - October 4, 1997 (Compilation), April-October 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Derechos humanos en Nicaragua: Informe anual Abril 1991 - Abril 1992, Centro Nicaraguense de Derechos Humanos, April 15, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - El Observador: Economico, No. 18. Fundacion Internacional para el Desafio Economico Global, June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Derechos humans en Nicaragua: Informe Anual Abril 1992 - Abril 1993, Centro Nicaraguense de Derechos Humanos, April 30, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mendes, Sklar, Herman. Glasnost and the Third World Environmental Activism Human Rights in Honduras, Nicaraguan Perspectives. Issue No. 18, Winter/Spring 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Covert Operations Against Nicaragua. A Public Forum, Campain for Political Rights, May 27, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - d'Escoto, Miguel. Nicaragua is More Christian Today, Bulletin 27, August 3, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Church and Revolution: A document of the Antonio Valdivieso Ecumenical Center, El Nuevo Diario, September 12, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Comentarios preliminares al documento de trabajo del ministerio de educacion 'fines y objetivos de la nueva educacion', UNAPAFACC-UPAFEC (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Sandinista Government States Policy on Religion in Nicaragua, Latinamerica Press, November 6, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Roqe'eta, Ko'aga. Impunidad y sus Efectos en los Procesos Democraticos, presentada en el Seminario Internacional, December 14, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Comunicado Oficial de la Direccion Nacional del FSLN sobre la religion, Direccion Nacional del Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Nicaragua Debe Optar Entre Consenso y Caos, Dice Watson, United States Information Service (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Nicaragua Country Report on Human Rights 1993, United States Information Service (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - 8 annexes about Nicaragua: History, Economy, Institutions, Human Rights, District Committees, Church and State, Election Results (no date or publisher) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Letra a Frente Sandinista del Pueblo Catolico. Conferencia Episcopal de Nicaragua, October 16, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - (Re) Estructuracion universitaria: Que profesional para que mundo/sociedad. Politicas universitarias norteamericanas / Desafios, convenios, financiamientos para la america latina, Universidad Centro America. Julio 25-28, 1994 (Propuesta), July 25-28, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Covert War Terror, Center for International Communication, Managua, Nicaragua (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Nicaragua's 1990 Elections, Nicaragua Network (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Ten Years of Democracy and Development, Nicaragua Network (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Centro de Educacion y Promocion Agraria. Cristo Campesino: Compromiso Cristiano. No. 7. February (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Ministerio de Educacion. Manual del brigadista. Cruzada Nacional de Alfabetizacion, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Official Communique of the National Directorate of the FSLN Concerning Religion (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Foro de Discusion de la Izquierda Democratica Sandinista Comision Coordinadora. Por la Unidad Revolucionaria del FSLN, February 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional. Plataforma Electoral 1997, May 1996 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Centro de Educacion y Promocion Agraria. Que es el Consejo de Estado. Diccionario Popular No.3, March 1981 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Committee of U.S. Citizens Living in Nicaragua. Cartoons from Nicaragua: The Revolutionary Humor of Roger, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Elections Nicaragua 1990. Human Rights: A Reply to America's Watch. Document 27, October 1, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Liberal National Unity Party. Elections Nicaragua 1990 Document 2 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Williams, Philip J. Dual Transitions from Authoritarian Rule: Popular and Electoral Democracy in Nicaragua. Comparative Politics, January 1994 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Adult Education in Nicaragua. Ministry of Education, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Romero, Rodolfo Delgado. La transicion en Nicaragua: Gobernabilidad, desarrollo y elecciones. Instituto de estudios nicaraguenses, November 20, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - La Gaceta. No. 6. Asamblea de la republica de nicaragua, January 9, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Exposicion de Motivos. Propuesto a la consideracion de la Honorable Asamblea Nacional de Nicaragua, May 10, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - CINCO, Las Mujeres como sujetos, ciudadanas, y opinantes decisivas para las elecciones de 1996(primera encuesta de opinion), Abril de 1996. Managua 14 pp, April 1996 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Peru, 10.
    - David Scott Palmer, Peru's Persistent Problems, January 1990 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Carol Wise, Post-War Peru: State Policy and Social Conflict Center for Politics and Policy, Claremont Graduate School, September 1992 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Special Topics, II.
  Materials such as murder manuals, Nicaraguan National Assembly, newspaper clippings, Nicaraguan elections, flyers, posters and brochures.
  - Murder Manuals, 1.
    - Murder Manuals. Letters, fact sheets concerning training manuals, memorandums, clippings, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Ministerio de la presidencia. "Base de datos de victimas de guerra." Enero de 1990, January 1990 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - National Assembly, 2.
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cuadro comparativo de las ponencias de los partidos politicos conforme: Guia de consulta nacional, sobre la constitucion de Nicaragua. Enero 24 de 1986, January 24, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Informe presentado por el Presidente de la Asamblea Nacional y de la comision especial constitucional sobre el primer proyecto de constitucion politica de Nicaragua. 21 de febrero de 1986, February 21, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Fuerzas armadas. 9 de julio de 1986, July 9, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Zonas especiales II y III. 10 de julio de 1986, July 10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos abiertos constitucionales, Zona Especial I, Aportes. 1 de julio de 1986, July 1, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Sector: Trabajadores de la salud. 10 de julio de 1986, July 10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Comerciantes. 9 de julio de 1986, July 9, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos abiertos constitucionales, Sector: Jovenes y maestros. 24 de junio de 1986, June 24, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildo abierto constitucional, Cristianos (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildo constitucionales, Productores agropecuarios industriales (Grandes, Medianos y Pequenos). 10 de julio de 1986, July 10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Obreros. 9 de julio de 1986, July 9, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Obreros. 10 de julio de 1986, July 10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildos constitucionales, Periodistas y trabajadores de la cultura. 10 de julio de 1986, July 10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Cabildo abierto constitucional, Mujeres (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Boletin. Summary I) Similarities, Variations, and Reservations in the Nicaraguan Constitutional Process II) Fundamental Contents of the Project of the New Constitution III) The Open Forums, February 1986 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Boletin. Sumario I) Parlamento latinoamericano por la paz y la democracia II) Resolucion de la UIP sobre centroamerica III) Solidaridad de academicos y juristas norteamericanos IV) Hacia los cabildos abiertos constitucionales. Abril 1986, April 1986 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Boletin. Summary I) The People Give Options at the Open Forums II) The Constitution Against Aggression III) Guatemalan Legislative Delegation Visits Nicaragua, May 1986 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Asamblea Nacional. Boletin. Contents I) The National Consultation and the Nicaraguan Constitution II) Legislative Activity of the Nicaraguan National Assembly III) Press Release Regarding the Case of Representative Felix Pedro Espinoza Briones, July 1986 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 3.
    - Salvadorans Sign Treaty to End the War New York Times, Jan. 17, 1992: Sec., A:l, 12, 13, January 17, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Doralisa Pilarte, Controvertible el Nombramiento. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 27,1990, April 27, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Hora de la Democracia Nica-(Newspaper Photographs of the inauguration of Violeta Barrios de Chamorro) (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Sergio Carrasco, La Contra se Aferra al Fusil. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 27, 1990, April 27, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Filadelfo Aleman, Disgusto por la Designacion. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 27, 1990, April 27, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Sergio Carrasco, A Todo Vapor. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 22,1990, April 22, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - El Gobierno Nica Niega el Ataque. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 9, 1990, April 9, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Sergio Carrasco, Asume el Mando y los Problemas. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 24, 1990, April 24, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Rodolfo Garcia, A Construir una Nueva Nicaragua. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 24, 1990, April 24, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Filadelfo Aleman. Advierten los Sandinistas sobre la 'Inestable Paz' Nica. El Nuevo Dia (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Atacan al Pacto de Desmovilizacion de los Contras. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 12, 1990, April 12, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Filadelfo Aleman, Denuncian una Ofensiva 'Contra' desde Honduras. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 17, 1990, April 17, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Rodolfo Garcia, Ortega Llama a la Oracion. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 17, 1990, April 17, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Pepo Garcia, Clama por Ayuda a los Nicas. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 17, 1990, April 17, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Filadelfo Aleman, Excluidos del Nuevo Gobierno Nica los Miembros del FSLN. El Nuevo Dia (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Inauguran la Primera Zona de Seguridad Nica. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 23, 1990, April 23, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Los Obreros Suben La Tension en Managua. El Nuevo Dia. Mayo 1, 1990, May 1, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Rodolfo Garcia, Desacreditan la Division en las Filas de Chamorro. El Nuevo Dia. Mayo 1, 1990, May 1, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Sergio Carrasco, El Otro Ortega Divide a la UNO. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 28,1990, April 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Oswaldo Bonilla, Pesimismo Economico. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 28, 1990, April 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Gary Silverman, Oposicion al Envio de EE.UU.. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 28, 1990, April 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Douglas Grant Mine, Fluye la Ayuda de la OEA. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 28, 1990, April 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Jose Antonio Maillo. Renuente a la Entrega de Armas la Contra. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 29, 1990, April 29, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Filadelfo Aleman. Chamorro Ante su Oposicion. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 28, 1990, April 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Rodolfo Garcia. Abren una Grieta Mayor a la Union. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 30, 1990, April 30, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Sergio Carrasco. A la Presidencia para Gestar la Paz. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 26, 1990, April 25, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Ortega Llevara una 'Oposicion Constructiva. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 25, 1990, April 25, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Filadelfo Aleman, Transicion Armoniosa. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 26, 1990, April 26, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Confian en la Paz las Familias de los Contras. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 25, 1990, April 25, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Sergio Castro. Toma el Control Politico y Militar. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 25, 1990, April 25, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Neil A. Lewis Wider C.I.A. Role Seen in Nicaragua, New York Times, July 18,1992. Sec. Y: 5 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Federico Fulleda, Victimas del Terror Dos Concejales Colombianos. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 22, 1990, April 22, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Oscar Serrat. De la Sedicion al Ruedo Politico. El Nuevo Dia. Abril 26, 1990, April 26, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - 5 Latin Presidents Defy U.S. and Urge Contras' Eviction, New York Times, Aug 8, 1989: Al, A8, August 8, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Democracy in Nicaragua Christian Science Monitor, 1989: 19, November 1989 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Propuesta de Paz de San Jose La Nation Febrero 16,1987: 16A, February 16, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Text of Nicaraguan Agreement on Cease Fire New York Times (Copy of the text as translated by the NYT), March 24, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - William Leogrande, How to Dispose of the Contras, New York Times, Sec. A:23+, August 9, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Nicaragua Holds Funds Tied to Vote, U.S. Asserts, Boston Globe, Jan 23, 1990, January 23, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Tim Johnson, Sandinistas Halt Brief Attempt at Friendship with Washington, The Miami Herald Aug. 18, 1992.. -- Nicaragua Ties Reforms to Unfreezing U.S. Aid he Miami Herald Aug. 20,1992: 13A, August 18, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Jennifer Bingham, In Break From Past, Nicaraguan Leftists Seek Closer Ties to US, The Christian Science Monitor Feb. 25, 1992: 1-2, February 25, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Larry Smith, I Had to Be Strong from the Beginning (an interview with Violeta Chamorro) Parade Magazine 1991: 4+, February 1991 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Why Were some Polls Wrong About the Nicaraguan Elections? The Hartford Courant, 1990: 4, March 7, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Nicaragua: Back to Square One? The Christian Science Monitor, December 13, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - David Clark Scott, Nicaragua Mayors Organize Chamorro's Coalition Woes and Spumed Vice President Becomes Chamorro Critic, The Christian Science Monitor, December 14, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Victor Borge y Jose Alberto Rodriguez, La Guerra de Encuestas en Nicaragua, La Nacion [Victor Borge and Jose Alberto Rodriguez, The Polling Wars in Nicaragua, La Nacion], March 3, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Norman Omstein, Why Polls Flopped in Nicaragua... and Howard Schuman, ...3 Different Pens Help Tell the Story, New York Times, March 7, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Lee Hockstader, Former Contras Scatter From Special Enclave, The Washington Post, July 15,1990: A 23 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Critican a Comision Ad Hoc por Actuar con Subjetividad El Diario de Hoy enero 16, 1993: 25, January 16, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Molina Olivares Dice Ve Amenazado Proceso de Paz (NOTIMEX) Enero 9 (Year?) (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Informe de la Verdad Podria Ser Publico: Cristiani (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - What Should U.S. Policy Be Toward Contras? San Francisco Chronicle, April 17, 1985,Sec A, 2 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Hiding the War in the White House, The New York Times, August 11, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Philip C. Roettinger, Fighting Talk, Guardian, July 18, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Wayne S. Smith, Mere Lip Service on Contadora, The New York Times, August 27, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Abraham Brumberg, Climate of an Undeclared War, The New York Times Book Review (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - U.S. Forsees Costly Fight in Latin America, The Plain Dealer, September 9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Missing Monitors, The Globe and Mail, November 30, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Vinas, Nadia. El indignante programa de 60 Minutes contra Guatemala editorial in Prensa Libre, Guatemala. Editorial deals with Jennifer Harbury story and reporting done by 60 Minutes, December 5, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Farah, Douglas. Political Twist in Nicaragua: the Divorce of Convenience, in The Washington Post, November 27, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Miscellaneous Articles on the FSLN infighting during 1994 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Knox, Paul. Clark advisers cool to observer role. Globe and Mail, October 25, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Unofficial Canadian group set to observe vote in Nicaragua. Toronto Star, October 29, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Electoral vitality in Nicaragua. Toronto Star (Editorial), November 7, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Ross, Oakland. Election called triumph of revolution, The Globe and Mail, November 6, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - An eye in Nicaragua, The Globe and Mail (Editorial), November 6, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Arseneault, Michel. Ottawa n'enverra pas d'observateurs aux elections nicaraguayennes Le Devoir, October 27, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Arseneault, Michel. Le scrutin nicaraguayen s'est deroule sans bavures Le Devoir, November 10, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Knox, Paul. Canadian observers satisfied by election (Publisher and day illegible), November 1984 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Election declared fair, The Prairie Messenger. November 26, 1984 (Editorial) (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Des Canadiens reclament une ambassade a Managua, Le Soleil, November 29, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - PCs urged to set up Nicaraguan embassy, The Gazette, November 29, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Embassy needed in Nicaragua, group tells Clark, The Globe and Mail, November 29, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Sutton, Robert. Canadian observers blast U.S. role in Nicaragua. Toronto Star, November 10, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Canadian church delegation observes Nicaraguan election. The Praire Messenger, November 5, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Mullens, Anne. Nicaragua vote observers urge Canada call for peace. The Sun, November 16, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Nicaraguan vote called 'free, fair'. Times-Colonist, November 15, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Knox, Paul. Vote-watcher finds decision unfair. Globe and Mail, October 30, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 144)